# Jennifer Kiesler

Sun Prairie, WI

Phone: (262) 994-8243 | Email: kiesler.jen@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/JenniferKiesler

Portfolio: https://jenniferkiesler.github.io/kiesler-react-portfolio/LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jennifer-kiesler-aa469591/

## Summary

A Software Developer with great problem solving skills. Has developed applications independently and as part of a group. Has acquired many transferable skills from previous work experiences including communication, collaboration, ability to adapt to change, and time management.

### **Technical Skills**

GitHub, Git, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, REST APIs, Agile, Node.js, Express.js, SQL, Postman, Sequelize, Handlebars, NoSQL, React, GraphQL, MERN

### **Projects**

Remembrall | https://github.com/jonpfluger/remembrall-game.git | https://lit-cove-97949.herokuapp.com/

- Full Stack application | Group project (5)
- This application lets a user play a Harry Potter themed memory card game.
- Created the spell cards and their function, and randomized and set the cards for each game
- React, MongoDB/Mongoose, GraphQL, Apollo Server, Apollo Client, Node.js/Express.js, Bootstrap

### House Rules | https://github.com/jonpfluger/house-rules.git | https://house-rules.herokuapp.com/

- Full Stack application | Group project (5)
- This application lets a user read posts about different types of games and write their own posts.
- JavaScript, Express.js, Sequelize, MySQL, Handlebars, Bootstrap, MVC, Anime.js, Cloudinary

### Toss Me A Book | https://github.com/JenniferKiesler/toss-me-a-book.git |

https://jenniferkiesler.github.io/toss-me-a-book/

- Front End application | Group project (4)
- Project Manager and Lead Engineer
- This application helps the user find a book in many different ways including subject, title, author, or just have the application pick a book from the NYT best seller list that comes with a short description of the
- HTML, CSS, Bulma, JavaScript, OpenLibrary API, Books API

## Anywhere Forecast | https://github.com/JenniferKiesler/anywhere-forecast.git |

https://jenniferkiesler.github.io/anywhere-forecast/

- Front End application
- This application is for someone wanting to see the weather or weather outlook for specific cities.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, OpenWeather API

### Neural Network API | https://github.com/JenniferKiesler/neural-network-api.git |

https://drive.google.com/file/d/1MRbFTvgvY1qxZLNrZG5JBLmUYCGX7dZG/view

- Back End NoSQL Database
- An API for a social network web application where users can share their thoughts, react to friends' thoughts, and create a friend list.
- Express.js, MongoDB, Mongoose

## Work Day Scheduler | https://github.com/JenniferKiesler/work-day-scheduler.git |

https://jenniferkiesler.github.io/work-day-scheduler/

- Front End application
- This application is a simple calendar that allows a user to save events for each hour of the work day.
- Time blocks change color depending on time.
- ¡Query, Bootstrap, Moment.js

#### Education

University of Wisconsin Coding Bootcamp (Madison, WI)	February 2023
Certificate in Full Stack Web Development	
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee (Milwaukee, WI)	May 2018
Biology and Chemistry Teaching Certifications	
University of Wisconsin-La Crosse (La Crosse, WI)	May 2014

Bachelor of Science (BS), Biology Major, Cellular/Molecular Emphasis, Chemistry Minor

### **Professional Experience**

### Science Teacher, Marshall High School (Marshall, WI)

August 2020-June 2021

- Taught 90 students in the allotted time frame by planning ahead and being adaptable which allowed for more successful lessons
- Differentiated lessons by determining which methods would work best for each class/individual student which allowed for more students to be successful in the classroom
- Communicated with parents by email or phone to ensure all students were successful and parents were up to date on the student's progress
- Adapted to teaching remote and in-class students at the same time by creating more virtual activities for all students to do which allowed for all students to be able to learn

### Science Teacher, Denmark High School (Denmark, WI)

August 2019-May 2020

- Collaborated with co-workers to create a new biology curriculum that met the new standards students should learn to be successful outside of high school
- Instructed and presented information in a clear, concise way by using multiple different methods including visual and audio to increase student learning

## Science Teacher, MC<sup>2</sup> High School (Milwaukee, WI)

August 2018-June 2019

- Developed the science department curriculum by organizing activities and units into a flowchart to make sure the different curriculums taught the students the standards required for that subject
- Ability to work under pressure by creating lesson plans for the week and to do lists which allowed everything to get done on time
- Analyzed the lessons by looking at the data and reflecting on how successful the lessons and activities were to determine whether the lesson worked or if the lesson needed to be adjusted and retaught

### Research Associate, Aurora Health Care (Milwaukee, WI)

June 2016-June 2017

- Maintained a lab notebook by organizing the notebook by date and providing in depth details about what was done each day including the assays done and the results which made analyzing and comparing data easier
- Improved the methods for processing different tumor samples and maintaining tissue cultures which increased the success of the tissue cultures growing
- Wrote and maintained a tissue culture database by assessing tissue cultures already in storage and growing multiple tissue cultures for storage which improved the process to find tissue samples needed for experiments and increased the amount of samples available for research

### Associate Research Specialist, UW - Madison (Madison, WI) September 2015-April 2016

- Trained 2 graduate and 3 undergraduate students by teaching different lab techniques to help the lab run more efficiently
- Problem solved unexpected results by analyzing data and troubleshooting to be sure everything was done properly and results were accurate and repeatable